Dream dangerously.
The Great Gatsby is a drama, romance film directed by Baz Luhrmann.
An adaptation of F.
Scott Fitzgerald's Long Island-set novel, where Midwesterner Nick Carraway
is lured into the lavish world of his neighbor, Jay Gatsby.
Soon enough, however, Carraway will see through the cracks of Gatsby's nouveau
riche existence, where obsession, madness, and tragedy await.
Jay Gatsby, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Nick Carraway, played by Tobey Maguire.
Daisy Buchanan, played by Carey Mulligan.
Tom Buchanan, played by Joel Edgerton.
Jordan Baker, played by Elizabeth Debicki.
Myrtle Wilson, played by Isla Fisher.
The Great Gatsby is a 2013 historical romantic drama
film based on the 1925 novel by F.
Scott Fitzgerald.
The film was co-written and directed by Baz Luhrmann and stars an ensemble cast consisting of Leonardo DiCaprio,
Tobey Maguire, Carey Mulligan, Joel Edgerton, Isla Fisher, Jason Clarke, and Elizabeth Debicki.
Filming took place from September to December 2011 in
Australia, with a $105 million net production budget.
The film follows the life and times of millionaire Jay Gatsby (DiCaprio) and his neighbor Nick Carraway (Maguire) who
recounts his interactions with Gatsby amid the riotous parties of the Jazz Age on Long Island in New York.
A polarizing film among critics, The Great Gatsby received both praise and criticism for its visual
style, direction, performances, soundtrack, and interpretation of the source material.
Audiences responded more positively, and Fitzgerald's granddaughter praised the film, stating "Scott would have been
proud." As of 2023, it is Luhrmann's highest-grossing film, grossing over $353 million worldwide.
At the 86th Academy Awards, the film won in both of its nominated
categories: Best Production Design and Best Costume Design.
The film explores themes of infidelity, based on novel or
book, obsession, hope, long island, new york.
The tone is emotional.